If you are copying what your competitors
are doing to get winning ads or you are
optimizing for volume because you don't
really know what is going to convert on
meta, then this video is for you because
I'm going to show you the easiest way to
make winning ads on meta. Now, every
time I hear one of these two things, I
always want to shake these founders or
media buyers or creative strategists by
the shoulders because what it tells me
is that they are actually really
insecure in the way that they are
approaching the platform. And there's no
shame in that because we've all been
there. But I have become so much more
confident as a creative strategist and a
founder knowing that I can always back
into these two frameworks and it makes
me feel like winning ad creatives is a
lot more of a for sure thing. And that's
just for me. That's just my own bias,
but I've also trained this to multiple
creative strategists and seen them make
it work. So, that's why I want to teach
you too. And I know what a lot of you
are thinking, but like if my competitors
are already winning with this, is isn't
that more of a for sure thing? And the
way that I like to think about this is
that if you are just going to be copying
what your competitors are doing, then
this is the equivalent of knowing that
you want to get married, aka grow your
business, but you're only going to strip
clubs, aka you are only stealing like
what is not yours and might not even be
the right thing for your customers. Now,
I want you to be operating from a more
secure place, from a place where you
feel like the strategy and ad creative
that you put forth is going to have a
much more higher likelihood of actually
converting on the platform and growing
your business ultimately. That's why
we're here. However, there are a few
basic principles that you're going to
have to understand before you actually
put these frameworks into action. So,
first, we are going to go over those
three core basic principles that is just
going to help you become a better
advertiser overall, but is really going
to help when you're going through the
workflows of these frameworks. The first
one is the big idea. This was really
popularized by David Ogilvy who
essentially said that the big idea is
the core unique and compelling creative
concept that drives an entire
advertising campaign, making a brand
stand out and compelling consumers to
buy. Without it, he famously noted, an
ad is likely just going to pass like a
ship in the night. He also said that he
doubts that one in a hundred ads have a
big idea. And something I want to note
is Ogilvy's best work happened in the
'50s and '60s. And I'd venture to say
that because there's so much more
advertising education out there today
that there are more big ideas at play.
And what I often teach when my creative
strategists are putting forward their
creative ideas and we're building out
road maps is that every single ad
creative that we have does have a big
idea or an essence. And I actually train
them when looking at different
advertisements to really succinctly be
able to state what the big idea behind
the ad creative is. Cuz if you're able
to do that, then it's going to be a lot
easier for you to, number two, another
big basic principle, to recognize the
patterns of what is actually working.
Now, pattern recognition is a mega
important for eCom advertisers or anyone
running meta ads, especially creative
strategists, because you need to be able
to spot trends and spot different types
of creatives that are working in your
niche or in your industry or in your ad
account. You need to be able to spot,
"Hey, this type of persona is actually
showing up in multiple winning ad
creatives. Wow, when we've done X, Y,
and Z, it hasn't actually performed as
well." I'd say that part of the reason
why I'm such a good creative strategist
cuz I have excellent pattern recognition
skills. It's not because I'm the most
creative, it's because I've really
trained myself to really be able to zoom
in on the big idea or the essence of a
creative and allow that to be a bit of a
beacon. So, when I am looking across an
ad account, I'm able to spot trends a
lot easier. And then number three is
prioritization. Again, mega, mega
important for anyone who is developing a
creative roadmap or developing a
strategy for Meta because what you are
essentially doing is developing your own
creative velocity and you're developing
a marketing plan over time specifically
for the platform. Now, what I find a lot
of creative strategists get wrong is
they aren't looking properly at this
type of access, right? Which is number
one, being able to prioritize what is
easiest to make. So, if they have a
really big creative idea that they want
to test, is there a simpler way for them
to validate their idea through a static,
through an internal creator, through
founders content before they spend a big
photo shoot budget on it. That's a
really big consideration and something
that as a creative strategy leader, I'm
often looking at when looking at our
roadmaps and I see, okay, this is going
to require that we hire a number of
creators to really execute this well,
but is there a way that we can get
validation on that idea sooner? Think
about what is quickest to make. The
other is what has the most likelihood to
actually perform. So, you know, even
when thinking about AI animation ads for
instance, I had a creative strat
recently put forward that they wanted to
do a musical and I was like, wow, number
one, that sounds like it's going to take
a lot of time and it does. These
animation ads are no joke and it also
sounds like something that I am not very
high confidence is actually going to be
a long-term scalable evergreen asset
because when we have made these
animation ads in the past, it's often
something that can, you know, get a
quick hit and convert really quick for a
specific audience, but isn't going to
have the evergreen lasting power of
something like a founders ad or a
partnership ad. So, this act of
prioritization is a really important
core fundamental when you are a creative
strategist and you're thinking about how
to make easily winning ad creative. What
is the easiest way to get that
validation? Or what do you have the most
evidence for in support of performance?
Now, the first framework is an idea that
I really want you to internalize, which
is that your next top performing
creative already likely exists in your
ad account in one way or another. And
particularly if you are spending more
than 100k per month or who you've spent
a million through your ad account, I
would venture to guess that if you were
able to look at your top 20 performing
creatives over the last year and you
were able to extract the big ideas from
these top performers and really
understand the pattern recognition, that
then it would be easy for you to see,
"Oh, wow. This ad creative should
actually be converted into another
format." So, this is one of my favorite
strategies is taking the core big
winning idea that has already proven to
have great performance in your ad
account, validated by how much it shows
up, aka that pattern recognition, and
then transferring that into a format
that is going to have more of an
emotional resonance. Often times, this
is creator content. I would highly
recommend doing it with partnership ads
now. So, this is actually an example of
an ad that I made a few years ago that
spent well over 2 million dollars for
the brand. And what's interesting to
note about it is I actually did this
exact framework to get this winning ad.
So, this was actually the complete ad
test that I ran for this brand. And
what's interesting to know is that all
of these messaging points were actually
taken from other top-performing
creative. So, the different headlines, I
was really extracting that big idea from
the ad itself and putting it as a
headline on the specific ad, which by
the way was a top performer, but it
wasn't the top performer like this one
ended up becoming. And specifically for
this winner, it was actually what was
said in the audio that I realized, "Oh,
I actually think what this is the big
idea versus this get ready with me
style." Right? Cuz she says, "Oh, I only
have 5 minutes before I have to jump on
this Zoom call."
>> I literally have a meeting starting in 3
minutes and I need to look like I didn't
just get out of bed.
>> It's not about get ready with me. No one
gives a about that. It's actually about,
"Hey, I'm going to be able to do this in
5 minutes," which is where I came up
with the 5-minute makeup routine. This
is another example of a top-performing
creative that my team made. And again,
this was taken from the big idea of
other top performers in an ad account. I
think you should see, "Hey, if you have
top-performing creatives that's in video
format, definitely try these big ideas
in statics." It's one of the best ways
to further develop a creative ecosystem.
So, what is a creative ecosystem, right?
A creative ecosystem is a combination of
ad creatives that really helps the user
have a cohesive journey and ultimately
make the sale. I know a lot of people
talk about creative diversity, but
something that I don't hear a lot of
advertisers talk about is, "Hey, your
big ideas actually need to show up in
multiple formats, you know, from
multiple creators to actually have real
scale power." The average person is
going to see your ads seven times before
they decide to buy in the best of cases.
So, the more times that you can have
that big idea and that proof show up
multiple times in a way that is still
entertaining, is still diversified, the
better for performance. This is
something that the brand Seed does so,
so well and is definitely a big reason
on why they are able to scale. They have
this core big creative learning and they
are not shy about having it show up
multiple times in creator content,
about, you know, putting out hundreds of
statics with this type of messaging each
quarter, hell, sometimes each month. So,
how long should you iterate on an ad
creative? Until it stops working. If you
haven't quite hit that level, I
encourage you to double back and run
through this framework so that you can
really squeeze more juice from the
fruits that you already have. Now, I
know what you're thinking at this point,
right? Well, what if we haven't spent a
ton on ads? What if we really don't have
those big core creative learnings just
yet? This is where I really like going
through our viral content SOP. This is
something that my business partner
Miguel really developed and this wasn't
something that I was doing super
consciously in the creative research
process, but is now a big fundamental
when we are onboarding a brand and
candidly, something that we do weekly
for a lot of our brands, especially as
we see this need and this push for more
top of funnel content. And essentially,
if you're going to be using organic
content, aka TikTok or Reels as your
inspiration point. So, we're going to be
taking your big creative idea, let's say
parents of picky eaters, and then you're
going to search for what is currently
going viral. And you'll know that you
find a really special piece of content
when smaller accounts are going viral
from these specific formats or messaging
angles. And again, leaning back into
your pattern recognition, notice what
tends to come up again and again. If
there are certain phrases, if there are
certain visuals, if there are even
certain settings or creators or types of
creators. These are all things that are
going to help you really zone in on a
more cohesive and a shared type of
strategy and ad creative.
>> Because ultimately, the patterns that
show up a lot should give you a lot more
confidence on what you're going to
execute on. And it's interesting. I know
that this works really well for brands
that maybe don't have a ton of data or
learnings on what type of core pillars
they should be executing on or big
ideas. But this is actually something
that we leaned into for a really big
brand as well. So they had a ton of
data, but we wanted to take a really big
swing on not only new concepts, but a
new persona that they haven't really
tested into that much. So even if you do
feel like you have a lot of big core
learnings, I think that this is actually
a better way to validate potential new
personas. And what I've actually done
is, "Hey, we see these big core concepts
or these big ideas as something that we
really want to test into." Also taking
these types of videos and scripts and
then running them through Run It, which
is Motion's new AI agent that lives
directly in Slack. This is actually my
preferred way right now to find personas
and really understand more of who our
personas are. Cuz something that I was
having a hard time getting around is
like, "Okay, you know, when we're doing
this persona-based research, I like to
do it in two ways. Number one, looking
at who our reviewers are and really
synthesizing through ad comments and
having the AI essentially spit out,
'Hey, here are your core personas.
Here's who's buying.'" The other thing
that I do is I take a look at all of the
ad creative that's currently running in
the ad account over the last 3 months
and I say, "Okay, who is the intended
audience from these?" And what I really
like to do is see, "Okay, based on who
our audience is currently and who we
seem to be targeting, is there a gap?"
That gap is often something that is a
really good place to start by testing ad
creatives so that you can essentially
fill that. But, what I've found is that
often times the people who are currently
buying the product aren't always the
people that are going to be the best
champion users of the product, right?
And depending on how good your strategy
is, you're likely not even targeting
them properly anyways with your ad
creative. So, by being able to look at
the different types of personas from
viral organic content and using that to
inform your strategy, this is something
that I have had a lot of lightbulb
moments with and winning ad creatives
from with my clients recently. So,
that's currently how I'm thinking about
it. If it's a little half-baked, it's
cuz it I'm still going through it. Now,
after going through both of these
frameworks, you should have a ton of
ideas written down. So, how do you know
which one to choose? I do have like a
sliding scale of evidence to help you
prioritize your creative ideas, but in
general, here's also how to think about
it. And I'll just say, number one, some
of it is gut. Sometimes, you're not
going to always have the right, you
know, percentage point of confidence
based on some Excel function sheet that
you developed. Or, you know, having
Claude tell you. Sometimes, it literally
is gut and you need to honor that,
especially as you're becoming more and
more advanced in your creative strategy
journey. But, if you do need help, this
sliding scale is something that helps me
know, "Okay, this is how I should
prioritize things." And another thing,
too, is you should really be
prioritizing what's going to give you
data the most quickly so that you can
act more quickly. This is often times
why when I am going through the first
framework, I like to get those statics
into action. And then finally, knowing
what has the biggest likelihood or
evidence to scale, which is likely going
to be creator content, specifically
partnership ads. And that is all that I
have for today. Thank you so much for
watching. I'll see you guys next week.
Love you. Bye.